<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Delhi &#8211; Shishir Raven</title>
	<atom:link href="https://shishirraven.github.io/iamshishir.com/category/delhi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://shishirraven.github.io/iamshishir.com/</link>
	<description>I code things</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 18:21:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/03101536/cropped-shishir_profie-e1662199926667-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Delhi &#8211; Shishir Raven</title>
	<link>https://shishirraven.github.io/iamshishir.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Am I Hopeful about  Delhi? Parking, Illegal Constructions, Cleanliness.</title>
		<link>https://shishirraven.github.io/iamshishir.com/2019/03/04/hopeful-about-delhi-parking-illegal-constructions-cleanliness/</link>
					<comments>https://shishirraven.github.io/iamshishir.com/2019/03/04/hopeful-about-delhi-parking-illegal-constructions-cleanliness/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shishir Raven]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 18:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Delhi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamshishir.com/?p=245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Growing population, Growing ProblemsDelhi is great for me in so many ways, a city where i was born and raised here, and spent all my entire life here until now. But the city has many growing concerns because the population is growing day by day. Work in progress everywhere.Driving through congested areas towards office me [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Growing population, Growing Problems</strong><br>Delhi is great for me in so many ways, a city where i was born and raised here, and spent all my entire life here until now. But the city has  many growing concerns because the population is growing day by day. </p>



<p><strong>Work in progress everywhere.</strong><br>Driving through congested areas towards office me and my cab driver has an interesting conversation about how the Delhi can be better, there are loads of illegal constructions going on in Delhi and so much constructions is in progress here and there. </p>



<p><strong>Are the people who come to delhi for work to blame?</strong><br>My Sardar Cab driver has a lot to say about the state. Mostly the blame went to the people who are from other states and in search of work land up to here. A place where anyone could find work and usually they stay wherever they can find shelter and slowly they build up their own slum dwellings. </p>



<p><strong>Illegally Possession of Public Property</strong><br>After a prolonged period it becomes as adverse possession. He told me that in the past Government has taken steps to remove the slum dwellings by giving free land and flats to these people. But what happens later is that these flats and lands are sold and they again return create slums wherever they can find space. </p>



<p><strong>My Cab driver says it&#8217;s hopeless!</strong><br>It was an interesting conversation. But he was not hopeful that anything positive can happen. And he was sure that government also can&#8217;t do anything (Kejriwal nor Modi). </p>



<p><strong>I am still hopeful!</strong><br>I am very hopeful that things can change. It&#8217;s only a matter of finding the right solution. It might take time but there is nothing which is impossible. This is what I believe. </p>



<p>Not everything can be solved in a day, but we can focus on most important issues and just start solving. </p>



<p><strong>A few things which I think should happen are according to me.</strong></p>



<ol><li><strong>Stop Illegal Constructions when they start happening</strong>. </li><li><strong>Focus on Education.</strong> If new Generations is Educated then they have better chances of finding good Jobs and home and who would not love to live in a better place or make their own place and surroundings better. </li><li><strong>Make strict rules for Parking</strong></li><li><strong>Make and Maintain better roads.</strong></li></ol>



<p>This is an interesting topic and I would love to discuss more about it with my cab driver today. But my destination arrived. </p>



<p>Write in comments what you think.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://shishirraven.github.io/iamshishir.com/2019/03/04/hopeful-about-delhi-parking-illegal-constructions-cleanliness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solutions to Delhi&#8217;s Air Pollution that I can think of.</title>
		<link>https://shishirraven.github.io/iamshishir.com/2018/12/12/air-that-we-breathe-is-getting-worse-but-what-is-the-solution/</link>
					<comments>https://shishirraven.github.io/iamshishir.com/2018/12/12/air-that-we-breathe-is-getting-worse-but-what-is-the-solution/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shishir Raven]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 22:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Delhi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/test/shishirraven/?p=17</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Living in delhi is great it&#8217;s pretty much a great city to live in. But there are some rising issues in our city such as as Pollution and Parking Space. Delhi attracts so many people from around India, especially because you can find work here. And mostly people look for that. With more people there [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<span id="more-17"></span>



<p>Living in delhi is great it&#8217;s pretty much a great city to live in. But there are some rising issues in our city such as as Pollution and Parking Space. Delhi attracts so many people from around India, especially because you can find work here. And mostly people look for that. With more people there is a need for more accomodation, more transportation and more energy.&nbsp;<br><br>Air is getting more toxic day by day because of the pollutants. Delhi is preparing for these situations for years. Like our bus and autos run on CNG which emits less pollutants than petrol and diesel. We have a pretty good Metro Network.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But all these in my opinion are failing because the Air Quality is declining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I am not an expert on the subject but If I had to solve the problem here are a few things I would have done.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="638" src="https://iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/image-1024x638.png" alt="" class="wp-image-40" srcset="https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095120/image-1024x638.png 1024w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095120/image-300x187.png 300w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095120/image-768x479.png 768w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095120/image.png 1284w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p class="has-huge-font-size"><strong>#1 Control Parking Spaces</strong><br></p>



<div class="wp-block-media-text alignwide"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img loading="lazy" width="675" height="477" src="https://iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/image-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-41" srcset="https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095124/image-1.png 675w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095124/image-1-300x212.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 675px) 100vw, 675px" /></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content">
<p>

In Delhi Parking is one of the greatest issues and improper parking causes so much inconvenience to all the people. Now take one case when the cars are parked on roads which are meant for transit. What happens they narrow down the roads and which in turn results in slower traffic and congestions. If the Delhi Government can focus on preventing these in appropriate parkings. It will solve the issue of having smoother traffic follow. And smoother traffic flow results in vehicle being lesser time on roads which equals to much lower Pollutions.&nbsp;

</p>
</div></div>



<p><br></p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-huge-font-size"><strong>#2 Maintain Smoother Roads.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-media-text alignwide has-media-on-the-right"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img loading="lazy" width="676" height="445" src="https://iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/image-3.png" alt="" class="wp-image-43" srcset="https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095125/image-3.png 676w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095125/image-3-300x197.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 676px) 100vw, 676px" /></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content">
<p>

Mostly the reason people spend so much time on the road is the condition of road itself. Potholes in the road and sometimes no road at all causes so much slowness in traffic. It&#8217;s one thing which is easier to implement and focusing on the better roads can result in lesser traffic.&nbsp;

</p>
</div></div>



<p><strong># Better Public Transport</strong><br>By adding Metro to Delhi was a great decision and it was done with quality. The project was executed with so much professionalism and speed. I also love the quality of travel by metro. But now with increasing number of travellers on issue is that too many people are stuffed into a metro which makes the travel uncomfortable. So if you have the means to take a Cab or your own car you will simply avoid it.&nbsp;<br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="918" height="608" src="https://iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/image-4.png" alt="" class="wp-image-44" srcset="https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095126/image-4.png 918w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095126/image-4-300x199.png 300w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/03095126/image-4-768x509.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 918px) 100vw, 918px" /></figure>



<p><br>In busses too it was a good move to bring in the AC Busses and I really appreciate the move. But when the bus are too overcrowded and have lesser frequency then you will take a bus only when you want to save money and spend more time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Government should improve the quality of service in these sectors and its very simple things which can yield results.&nbsp;</p>



<ol><li>Increase the no of bus so that people are not stuffed into the bus but have enough breathing space.&nbsp;</li><li>Make it more convenient to travel. In the current situation if you take a bus the experience is like this. First you board the bus and then hustle to get your ticket. then squeezing to find a spot to stand if you do not find a seat. And then the private bus just makes stops on a bus stop for like up to 5-7 minutes to get as much passengers as they get (More passengers = More money). This is not a convenient experience at all. And moreover waiting for the bus adds to the time. These are not difficult to solve. People stuff into the busses because the no of busses which are in service are really lesser than they should be. At peak hours these busses should increased. The stoppage time should be limited to only for a minute or two. The Bus should provide high Speed internet to the travelers. There should be smart cards that would allow the users to pay for the ticket easily because getting the right change is also always and issue while buying tickets.&nbsp;</li><li>Encourage Shared Cabs. Shared cabs ensures that we fully utilize the vehicle used. It 4 people travelling can use the same cab instead of using 4 different vehicles it definitely saves so much energy consumption, frees the road. All this co-relate to cleaner air.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<p>Please leave comment on what you think is a solution.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://shishirraven.github.io/iamshishir.com/2018/12/12/air-that-we-breathe-is-getting-worse-but-what-is-the-solution/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
