<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Inspirational &#8211; Shishir Raven</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/inspirational/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>I code things</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 20:48:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/03101536/cropped-shishir_profie-e1662199926667-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Inspirational &#8211; Shishir Raven</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Carpe Diem</title>
		<link>/2019/03/11/carpe-diem/</link>
					<comments>/2019/03/11/carpe-diem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shishir Raven]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 20:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspirational]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamshishir.com/?p=320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carpe Diem (Exclamation!) Used to urge someone to make the most of the present time and give little thought to the future I first saw it tattooed on the arm of a good friend. Yesterday I watched &#8220;Dead Poets Society&#8220;, an amazing movie and as you guessed Carpe Diem is the movie&#8217;s theme. It tells [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Carpe Diem  (Exclamation!)  <br>Used to urge someone to make the most of the present time and give little thought to the future</p></blockquote>



<span id="more-320"></span>



<p>I first saw it tattooed on the arm of a good friend.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-QwWZrCyQfgg/UYpluC0uxnI/AAAAAAAAASk/ZCMa1J5s_Wkm3GwQDRxAF-FF8X3Sezm1wCJkCGAYYCw/w1082-h609-n-rw-no/532029_3509784563430_1485051926_n.jpg" alt="Image result for amit nair carpe diem"/><figcaption>Carpe Diem on my friend Amit Nair&#8217;s arm. </figcaption></figure></div>



<p> Yesterday I watched &#8220;<strong>Dead Poets Society</strong>&#8220;, an amazing movie and as you guessed <strong>Carpe Diem</strong> is the movie&#8217;s theme.  <br><br>It tells the story of an English teacher who inspires his students through his teaching of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poetry">poetry</a>. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" width="465" height="559" src="https://iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/image-17.png" alt="" class="wp-image-373" srcset="https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/03095313/image-17.png 465w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/03095313/image-17-250x300.png 250w" sizes="(max-width: 465px) 100vw, 465px" /></figure></div>



<p>There is so much that we can take from the movie and it&#8217;s a must watch. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Dead_poets_society.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-322" width="167" height="250" srcset="https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/03095307/Dead_poets_society.jpg 258w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/live.iamshishir.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/03095307/Dead_poets_society-201x300.jpg 201w" sizes="(max-width: 167px) 100vw, 167px" /><figcaption>Cover Dead Poets Society</figcaption></figure></div>



<div class="wp-block-ugb-button ugb-button-wrapper ugb-button--align-center"><div><a class="ugb-button ugb-button--align-center ugb-button--size-normal ugb-button--has-icon" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0097165/" style="border-radius:4px"><svg aria-hidden="true" data-icon="imdb" class="svg-inline--fa ugbfa-imdb fa-w-14 " role="img" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewbox="0 0 448 512" value="fab-imdb"><path fill="currentColor" d="M400 32H48C21.5 32 0 53.5 0 80v352c0 26.5 21.5 48 48 48h352c26.5 0 48-21.5 48-48V80c0-26.5-21.5-48-48-48zM21.3 229.2H21c.1-.1.2-.3.3-.4zM97 319.8H64V192h33zm113.2 0h-28.7v-86.4l-11.6 86.4h-20.6l-12.2-84.5v84.5h-29V192h42.8c3.3 19.8 6 39.9 8.7 59.9l7.6-59.9h43zm11.4 0V192h24.6c17.6 0 44.7-1.6 49 20.9 1.7 7.6 1.4 16.3 1.4 24.4 0 88.5 11.1 82.6-75 82.5zm160.9-29.2c0 15.7-2.4 30.9-22.2 30.9-9 0-15.2-3-20.9-9.8l-1.9 8.1h-29.8V192h31.7v41.7c6-6.5 12-9.2 20.9-9.2 21.4 0 22.2 12.8 22.2 30.1zM265 229.9c0-9.7 1.6-16-10.3-16v83.7c12.2.3 10.3-8.7 10.3-18.4zm85.5 26.1c0-5.4 1.1-12.7-6.2-12.7-6 0-4.9 8.9-4.9 12.7 0 .6-1.1 39.6 1.1 44.7.8 1.6 2.2 2.4 3.8 2.4 7.8 0 6.2-9 6.2-14.4z"></path></svg><span class="ugb-button--inner">Dead Poets Society on&nbsp; IMDB</span></a></div></div>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">? As says the movie and the tattoo on my friends arm, I urge too. Carpe Diem.</p>



<h2>How easy it is to drift ? through life without doing what really makes you happy. </h2>



<p>We sometime make life a routine. eat, work, sleep and repeat. And this routine may just fall into place with no special intervention.  <br></p>



<p>Our attention though life goes on schemes to earn money. <br>More money so that we can pay of our EMI&#8217;s and Loans&#8230; for house, for car&#8230;for education and &#8230; whatever.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>We sometimes just grow older. But we do not grow happier. </p></blockquote>



<p>Shouldn&#8217;t we grow happier and more content with age?</p>



<p>Thus so, it is important to be connected with our own emotions and happiness. Plus it is important to live fearlessly and hopefully. Just working hard is not enough. It&#8217;s important to enjoy and excel in what you do. Also it&#8217;s easier to excel in what you are naturally interested in. </p>



<p>You might have to choose between a lucrative safe career which does not interesting to you and a risky career with lots of things that excite you. While deciding, keep in mind that your thoughts will always be there where your heart is. Being on a job with your heart wandering  elsewhere will never make you happy. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>We should live such that when we look back at our life we see a legacy.</p></blockquote>



<p>Years from now when you look back, you would love to see yourself  as a <strong>brave warrior who lived fearlessly.</strong> ?<br><br>It would be really sad if you look back and see yourself as a person who lived life just to have good and secure retired life. ?</p>



<p><strong>Hey, One way or the other life is going to end. </strong>?. <strong>So Decide. </strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-ugb-divider ugb-divider"><hr align="center" style="background-color:#dddddd;width:50%;height:1px"/></div>



<blockquote style="text-align:center" class="wp-block-quote"><p>?  Seek happiness Boldly. </p><p>? Attempt life heartfully. <br></p><p>?Chart your own path to your dreams.  </p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-ugb-divider ugb-divider"><hr align="center" style="background-color:#dddddd;width:50%;height:1px"/></div>



<h2>?Around 3 years back &#8230; I quit doing good to do great. </h2>



<p>I quit my job to start <a href="http://www.thewebfort.com/">Webfort Technologies</a> with a close friend 3 years back. I had a successful career and I was good at my Job. Also I was appreciated for my work. But I wanted more freedom. Instead of working on projects with fixed timelines and fixed budgets. I wanted to work on long term projects. Projects where there will be freedom and no restraint of time and money. </p>



<p>Life and people were good back then, but I was not growing any happier. Salary was rising steadily. But I started feeling that I am just a important cog of a big machine. </p>



<p><strong>I wanted more&#8230;</strong> I felt trapped in a loop. I wanted more free time to build what I believed in. So when I got a chance, I quit. It wasn&#8217;t easy to choose between a nurtured career with its own securities and more freedom with its own risks. </p>



<p>? <strong>Today I am more happier than ever, I can work when I want, where I want and on what I want. </strong>I have a great team. It&#8217;s so much fun now. Not a day feels like work. Work doesn&#8217;t feel work and it happens naturally and quitely.  </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>It may sound crazy but I miss going to office on Sundays. ?</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-ugb-divider ugb-divider"><hr align="center" style="background-color:#dddddd;width:50%;height:1px"/></div>



<h2><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/26a0.png" alt="⚠" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Caution: With a grain of Salt please.</h2>



<p>I do not recommend that you should quit your jobs. </p>



<p>But I do recommend that you<strong> get in touch </strong>?<strong> with your real aspirations. </strong>Work towards seeking and pursuing them. </p>



<p>Turning aspirations into professions might not always be possible. Like you might love music and dance. But though it is your love, it might take practice to get good at it so that you may take it up professionally. <br><br>What I urge is whenever you get time and chance, do what you love. If singing and dancing makes you happy at heart then do it. ???</p>



<h2>Every Job comes with great learning opportunities.</h2>



<p>And you can use them to sharpen yourself. Long before I started to feel trapped in my Job, I felt constantly challenged.  Every job and position i held came with a challenge and I tried to give it all I had.</p>



<p>I would confess that I failed more than I succeeded. But eventually after trying &amp; failing too many times you start winning and you move a level up. ?</p>



<h2>During those awesome days as an employee ?&#x200d;?. I learned everything.</h2>



<p>Working with people from all around the Globe back then taught me so much. <br><br><strong>I learned how to plan projects, build a team and mentor people. </strong>Leading people but upwards, downwards and sideways. Encouraging people and learning almost every skill necessary. I learnt how to make others grow so that you I grow. <strong>I was an introvert guy initially, a person who just minds his own business. But it took time for me to change and work with people.</strong> All this happened on my previous jobs. </p>



<h2>? Waiting for the opportunity and preparation is important. </h2>



<p>Before doing great things for myself. I did great things for companies and clients who hired me. I was sincere and honest to every job and task I was assigned. </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>??Quitting job for a startup came naturally when I was ready and gave way for bigger challenges. </p></blockquote>



<p>Believe me easier life does not mean a happier one. After quitting, work did not became easier, it became more challenging. </p>



<p>After all difficult game keeps you occupied than an easy one. <br>You just can&#8217;t surf on a calm sea. </p>



<p>Certainty also bring boredom. <br>But uncertainty keeps you alive, active and alert. I am constantly challenged in the role of leading but these challenges are necessary to keep me strong and growing. <br><br>And I hope challenges never end.  ?</p>



<div class="wp-block-ugb-divider ugb-divider"><hr align="center" style="background-color:#dddddd;width:50%;height:1px"/></div>



<p>I share below a <strong>beautiful and famous poem by Robert Frost. </strong><br>I love the last  stanza.<br></p>



<h2><strong>The Road not taken</strong> </h2>



<p>Two roads diverged in a yellow wood,<br>And sorry I could not travel both<br>And be one traveler, long I stood<br>And looked down one as far as I could<br>To where it bent in the undergrowth;</p>



<p>Then took the other, as just as fair,<br>And having perhaps the better claim,<br>Because it was grassy and wanted wear;<br>Though as for that the passing there<br>Had worn them really about the same,</p>



<p>And both that morning equally lay<br>In leaves no step had trodden black.<br>Oh, I kept the first for another day!<br>Yet knowing how way leads on to way,<br>I doubted if I should ever come back.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I shall be telling this with a sigh<br>Somewhere ages and ages hence:<br><strong>Two roads diverged in a wood, and I—<br>I took the one less traveled by,<br>And that has made all the difference.</strong></p></blockquote>



<p>? Please share what you feel in comments. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/270a.png" alt="✊" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <strong>Carpe Diem</strong> </p><p><br></p></blockquote></figure>



<div class="wp-block-ugb-divider ugb-divider"><hr align="center" style="background-color:#dddddd;width:50%;height:1px"/></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/03/11/carpe-diem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
